Inventory of the Linda Carol Friend Adams Papers 1965-2008
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Linda Carol Friend Adams Papers 1998-2008 2000-2008
Special Collections Research Center
01/Mss abcxyz
5.00
The collection includes the genealogical research of Linda Carol Friend Adams. It contains a number of state and county records, family documents, biographical information, emails, message board posts, research notes, and photographs that concern Adams' family history.
Adams, Linda Friend, 1943-2008 arrangement
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Biographical Note
Linda Carol Friend Adams was born on March 26, 1943 in Charlestown, West Virginia. She grew up in the towns of Ivydale and Clay, also in West Virginia, before moving to Williamsburg in 1960 to be closer to family. Adams worked as a secretary at the Williamsburg Methodist Church for six years. She also became a part-time student at the College of William and Mary, graduating with a B.A. in English in 1973. In October of 1966, she took the position of Secretary to the Curator of Manuscripts and Receptionist for Special Collections at Swem Library. She married Raymond Alexander Adams, Jr. in August of 1977.
Adams held several positions during her tenure at Swem Library, including Secretary to the Head Librarian, Head of the Reserve Room, and Coordinator of Circulation Services. She retired in 1998, after 32 years of service.
After retiring, Adams extensively researched her family's genealogy. She became involved with a number of historical organizations. She joined the Williamsburg chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution, and served as Recording Secretary for one year and Chapter Registrar for four. Adams also became a member of the Descendants of Washington's Army at Valley Forge, the National Society of United States Daughters of 1812, and the United Daughters of the Confederacy.
Linda Friend Adams died on September 6, 2008 in Williamsburg at the age of 65.
Scope and Contents
The collection includes the genealogical research of Linda Carol Friend Adams. It contains a number of state and county records, family documents, biographical information, emails, message board posts, research notes, and photographs that concern Adams' family history.
The majority of Adams' ancestors were located in Virginia and West Virginia. The information included here pertains to the following families (not a complete list): Adams, Allen, Barnett, Blake, Brasfield, Brock, Burns, Chapman, Cutlip, Dawson, Drake, Friend, Henley, Hill, Long, Mayo, Mosby, McClure, McCune, O'Brian, Parke, Riddle, Rogers, Rose, Semple, Sheetz, Skidmore, Smith, Stevenson, Watson, Williams, Wilson.
Arrangement of Materials
The collection is organized into the following series and sub series: Series 1: Genealogy of Linda Carol Friend Adams, 1965-2008; Sub-series 1: Lineage of Carol Friend Adams, 2006; Sub-series 2: Genealogical Reserach, 1999-2008; Sub-series 3: Supplemental Materials, 1965-2008; Series 2: Genealogical and Historical Organizations, 1973-2008; Sub-series 1: Miscellaneous Historical Organizations, 1973-2008; Sub-series 2: United Daughters of the Confederacy, 2005-2008; Sub-series 3: National Society of the United States Daughters of 1812, 2006-2008; Sub-series 4: Descendants of Washington's Army at Valley Forge, 2002-2008; Sub-series 5: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1999-2008.
Additional Information
Index Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Corporate Name:
College of William and Mary--Swem Library
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Genealogies; Photocopies; Photographs
Topical Term:
United States--History--Revolution, 1775-1783.
Detailed Description of the Collection
  Series 1: Genealogy of Linda Carol Friend Adams
- Genealogy of Linda Carol Friend Adams, 1965-2008
  This series contains documents, images, correspondence, and research concerning Linda Adams' genealogy. Most of the information is organized and compiled into a set of 10 three-ring binders. Additional binders and folders contain further information on her lineage, as well as her research notes.
    Subseries 1: Lineage of Linda Carol Friend Adams
  - Lineage of Linda Carol Friend Adams, 2006 (1)
    This sub-series consists of a set of 10 three-ring binders composed and organized by Linda Adams. Beginning with an Ahnentafel Ancestry Chart, Adams traces her lineage back through 13 generations. Documents include birth and death certificates, marriage licenses, county and military records, census data, biographical information, and photographs. The information included pertains to the following families (not a complete list): Adams, Allen, Barnett, Blake, Brasfield, Brock, Burns, Chapman, Cutlip, Dawson, Drake, Friend, Henley, Hill, Long, Mayo, Mosby, McClure, McCune, O'Brian, Parke, Riddle, Rogers, Rose, Semple, Sheetz, Skidmore, Smith, Stevenson, Watson, Williams, Wilson.
    - Lineage of Linda Carol Friend Adams, vol. 1-5, 2006 (1)
      This box contains the first five volumes of Linda Adams' genealogy project.
    - Lineage of Linda Carol Friend Adams, vol. VI-X, 2006 (1, 2)
      This box contains the second half of Linda Adams' genealogy project.
    Subseries 2: Genealogical Research
  - Genealogical Research, 1999-2008 (2)
    This sub-series consists of supplemental genealogical infomation collected by Linda Adams. The range of documents include birth and death certificates, marriage licenses, county and military records, census data, biographical information, and photographs, as well as extensive research notes. The information included pertains to the following families (not a complete list): Adams, Allen, Barnett, Blake, Brasfield, Brock, Burns, Chapman, Cutlip, Dawson, Drake, Friend, Henley, Hill, Long, Mayo, Mosby, McClure, McCune, O'Brian, Parke, Riddle, Rogers, Rose, Semple, Sheetz, Skidmore, Smith, Stevenson, Watson, Williams, Wilson. There has been an attempt to maintain Adams' organization of these folders and documents as much as possible.
    - (2, 3)
      - Allen, Drake, Parke, Riddle, Smith Research, 1999-2005 (2, 3)
        Grey three-ring binder organized by Linda Carol Adams. Includes research, documents, correspondence, and images concerning the Allen, Drake, Hill, Parke, Riddle, and Smith families.
      - Dawson & Related Research, 1998-2005 (2, 3)
        Black three-ring binder composed and organized by Linda Adams. Includes research, documents, correspondence, and images pertaining to the Dawson, Rose, and McCune families.
      - Long Family with Burkett, Etris, Whitmore Research, 1999-2006 (2, 3)
        Black three-ring binder composed and organized by Linda Adams. Includes research, documents, correspondence, and images concerning the Long, Burkett, Etris, and Whitmore families.
      - McCune/O'Brian Research, 2002-2003 (2, 3)
        Blue three-ring binder composed and organized by Linda Adams. Includes research, documents, correspondence, and images relating to the McCune, Rose, and O'Brian families.
      - Williams Research, 1999-2006 (2, 3)
        Grey three-ring binder composed and organized by Linda Adams. Includes research, documents, correspondence, and images relating to the Williams and Jones families.
    - (2, 4)
      - Dawson, Mosby, Sheetz, Barnett research, 2001-2007 (2, 4, 1)
        Research documents and correspondence compiled by Linda Adams on the Dawson, Mosby, Sheetz, and Barnett families.
      - Williams and Burns research, 2002-2005 (2, 4)
        Research documents and correspondence compiled by Linda Adams on the Williams and Burns families.
      - Williams DNA test correspondence, 2007 (2, 4, 3)
        A collection of printed emails between Linda Adams and others concerning a DNA test among geneaologists to prove relationship to the Williams family line.
      - Brock, Brasfield, and Adams research, 2002-2006 (2, 4)
        Research documents and correspondence compiled by Linda Adams on the Brock, Brasfield, and Adams families.
      - Adams DNA test information, 2008 (2, 4, 5)
        Information and results concerning a DNA test taken by Raymond A. Adams, Linda Adams' husband.
      - Long and Sheetz research, 2003?-2004? (2, 4, 6)
        Research documents and correspondence compiled by Linda Adams on the Long and Sheetz families.
      - James Smith supplement, ?-2006 (2, 4, 7)
        Research documents and correspondence compiled by Linda Adams on James Smith of Virginia.
      - Friend, Blake, Davis, Hill, Smith, Skidmore, McClure, and Cutlip research, 2006-2008 (2, 4, 8)
        Research documents and correspondence compiled by Linda Adams on the Friend, Blake, Davis, Hill, Smith, Skidmore, McClure, and Cutlip families.
      - Mayo and Henley research, 2008 (2, 4, 9)
        Research documents and correspondence compiled by Linda Adams on the Mayo and Henley families.
      - Research shared with/connected to Rev. Albert Elswick (includes Semple, Wilson, Watson, and Stevenson families), 2001-2005 (2, 4, 10)
        This folder contains correspondence and documents exchanged with or connected to Rev. Albert Elswick, a distant cousin of Linda Adams. Information is included on the following families (not a complete list): Semple, Wilson, Watson, and Stevenson.
      - Research from Rev. Albert Elswick, March 2003 (2, 4, 11)
        This folder contains the contents of an envelope sent to Linda Adams from Rev. Albert Elswick. Includes information on the Semple and Wilson families from Pennsylvania, as well as a photograph labeled "Jeremiah Butler's 'tooth puller.'"
      - Research from Rev. Albert Elswick, December 2004 (2, 4, 12)
        This folder contains the contents of an envelope sent to Linda Adams from Rev. Albert Elswick. Includes information on the Semple and Stevenson families of Pennsylvania, as well as photographs of a cemetary.
      - Miscellaneous genealogical research, 2003?-2008 (2, 4, 13)
        This folder contains information and notes on various families that were not organized within the rest of the collection.
      - Research notes, ?-2008 (2, 4, 14)
        This folder contains a variety of Linda Adams' genealogy research notes.
      - Friend, Frame, and Harris research, 2003-2006 (2, 4)
        Black three-ring binder composed and organized by Linda Adams. Includes research, documents, correspondence, and images relating to the Friend, Frame, and Harris families.
      - Drake, Hill, Smith, Allen research, 2003-2006 (2, 4)
        Blue file composed and organized by Linda Adams. Includes printed emails, message board posts, and library catalog search results pertaining to research on the Drake, Hill, Smith, and Allen families.
    Subseries 3: Supplemental Materials
  - Supplemental Materials, 1965-2008 (3)
    This sub-series includes the various correspondence of Linda Adams, the majority of which consists of printed emails and message board posts with other genealogists. Photographs of gravestones and historical markers connected to Adams' research are also included.
    - (3, 4)
      - Letters, emails, message board posts, 1999-2008 (3, 4, 15)
        This folder contains a variety of letters, printed emails, and copies of message board postings relating to Linda Adams interest and research in genealogy.
      - Photographs and negatives, undated (3, 4, 16)
        This folder contains negatives and photographs included with Linda Adams' genealogy research. Includes photos of gravestones and Fort Donnally.
      - Augusta and Greenbrier Counties, West Virginia research, published 1965-1988 (3, 4, 17)
        Contains photocopied excerpts of documents relating to the history of Augusta and Greenbrier Counties in West Virginia.
      - Ritchie County, West Virginia research, 2004-2005 (3, 4, 18)
        This folder contains information concerning Linda Adams' research of Ritchie County, West Virginia.
      - Virginia Revolutionary Publick Claims, vol. 3, compiled by Janice L. Abercrombie and Richard Slatten, undated (3, 4, 19)
        Copied exceprts of the "Virginia Revolutionary Publick Claims," vol. 3 by Janice L. Abercrombie an Richard Slatten.
      - Hampshire Country Minute Book Abstracts, 1788-1802, compiled by Vicki Bidinger Horton, 1993 (3, 4, 20)
        Exceprts of "Hampshire County Minute Book Abstracts" compiled by Vicki Bidinger Horton.
    - (3, 5)
  Series 2: Genealogical and Historical Organizations
- Genealogical and Historical Organizations, 1973-2008
  This series contains materials relating to Linda Adams' involvement in a variety of genealogical and historical societies. Included are files concerning her membership in the United Daughters of the Confederacy, National Society of United States Daughters of 1812, Descendants of Washington's Army at Valley Forge, and the Daughters of the American Revolution.
    Subseries 1: Miscellaneous Historical Societies
  - Miscellaneous Historical Societies, 1973-2008 (1)
    This sub-series contains information and publications on a variety of historical societies that Linda Adams was a member of or used in her research.
    - (1, 5)
      - Miscellaneous Historical Society Information and Publications, 1982-2007 (1, 5)
      - Greenbrier Historical Society, 2004-2006 (1, 5, 2)
        Contains newsletters and journals from the Greenbrier Historical Society of West Virginia.
      - Henckel Genealogical Bulletin, 1973-2002 (1, 5, 3)
    Subseries 2: United Daughters of the Confederacy
  - United Daughters of the Confederacy, 2005-2008 (2)
    This sub-series includes information relating to Linda Adams' membership in the United Daughters of the Confederacy. Her qualifying ancestors are listed as Oliver M. McButler and Richard Williams.
    - (2, 5)
      - United Daughters of the Confederacy application and membership, 2005-2008 (2, 5, 4)
        This folder contains application and membership information, promotional materials, research and correspondence relating to Linda Adams' association with the Daughters of the Confederacy. Her qualifying ancestor is listed as Oliver M. McButler of Virginia.
      - United Daughters of the Confederacy, Williams supplement, 2006-2007 (2, 5)
        Contains research information and documents concerning Linda Adams' ancestor Richard Williams in realtion to her membership in the Daughters of the Confederacy.
    Subseries 3: National Society of United States Daughters of 1812
  - National Society of United States Daughters of 1812, 2006-2008 (3)
    This subseries includes information relating to Linda Adams' association with the United States Daughters of 1812. Her qualifying ancestor is listed as Andrew Skidmore from Virginia.
    - (3, 5)
      - National Society of United States Daughters of 1812, 2006-2008 (3, 5)
        Contains membership application, genealogical research, newsletters, and correspondence relating to Linda Adams' association with the United States Daughters of 1812. Her qualifying ancestor is listed as Andrew Skidmore from Virginia.
    Subseries 4: Descendants of Washington's Army at Valley Forge
  - Descendants of Washington's Army at Valley Forge, 2002-2008 (4)
    This sub-series includes information on Linda Adams' membership with the Descendants of Washington's Army at Valley Forge. Her qualifying ancestor is listed as John McCollum.
    - (4, 5)
      - Descendants of Washington's Army at Valley Forge, 2002-2008 (4, 5, 7)
        Contains application information, correspondence, newsletters, and reserach infomation on Linda Adams' association with the Descendants of Valley Forge. Her qualifying ancestor is listed as John McCollum from Virginia.
    Subseries 5: National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution
  - National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution, 1999-2008 (5)
    This sub-series includes a range of documents relating to Linda Adams' involvement in the National Society of the Daughters of the American Revolution (DAR). There has been an attempt to maintain as much of her organization of these folders and documents as possible.
    - (5)
      - Daughters of the American Revolution correspondence, chapter activites, miscellaneous, 2002-2008 (5, 8)
        This folder contains correspondence, chapter information, and news clippings concerning Linda Adams' role as a member of the Williamsburg chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Rose supplement, 2002-2003 (5, 9)
        Contains research information on Issac Rose, one of Linda Adams' qualifying ancestors for the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, McCollum supplement, 2002-2003 (5, 10)
        Contains research information on John McCollum, one of Linda Adams qualifying ancestors in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, McClure supplement, 2003-2004 (5, 11)
        Contains research information on Arthur McClure, one of Linda Adams' qualifying ancestors in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Sheetz supplement, 2004-2006 (5, 12)
        Contains research information on Jacob Sheetz, one of Linda Adams' qualifying ancestors in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Dawson supplement, 2007-2008 (5, 13)
        Contains research information and other DAR applications in realtion to John Dawson, one of Linda Adams' qualifying ancestors in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Chapman supplement, undated (5, 14)
        Contains research information on Jacob Chapman, one of Linda Adams' qualifying ancestors in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Hinkel, Skidmore, and Chapman supplements, 2002-2008 (5, 15)
        This folder contains miscellaneous reserach information and documents collected by Linda Adams on four of her qualifying ancestors in the DAR: Maria Magdalena Eschmann Hinkle, John Justus Hinkle, Sr., Agnes Caldwell Skidmore, John Skidmore, and Jacob Chapman.
      - Battle of Green Spring Veterans research, 2006-2007 (5, 16)
        Contains correspondence and research into the Virginians who fought during the American Revolution.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Drake supplement (for Oma Hendrick Mills), undated (5, 17)
        Contains a membership application and research information from Oma Henricks Mills. She and Linda Adams both claim George Drake as a qualifying ancestor in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Henckel supplement (for Harriet Doughman Rosentahl), 1999 (5, 18)
        Contains the membership application for Harriet Doughman Rosentahl. She and Linda Adams both claim John Justus Henckel/Hinckel as a qualifying ancestor in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution, Allen supplement (for Kathleen Curren Wasem), 2004 (5, 19)
        Contains membership application and research information for Kathleen Curren Wasem. She and Linda Adams both claim Joshua B. Allen as a qualifying ancestor in the DAR.
      - Daughters of the American Revolution supplements, 2001-2008 (5)
        This red binder contains research, correspondence, and membership records relating to three of Linda Adams' qualifying ancestors in the DAR: Aaron Smith, George Drake, and Joshua B. Allen.